<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BuLLeKeUp&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://bullekeup.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on BuLLeKeUp&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 09:08:44 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://bullekeup.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GEIPI 1A - Mini-projets TD</title>
      <link>https://bullekeup.github.io/courses/geipi_1a_mini_projet_td/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 09:44:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bullekeup.github.io/courses/geipi_1a_mini_projet_td/</guid>
      <description>Consignes mini-projets TD de programmation C/C++ Ces mini-projets ont pour but de vous confronter à la programmation avec un objectif concret, en utilisant les notions théoriques vues en cours.
Sujets Jeux d&amp;rsquo;automates cellulaires avec différents algorithmes Réaliser un jeu de la vie de Conway en C++. Chaque début de nouvelle partie doit être généré aléatoirement. Votre programme devra pouvoir sauvegarder son état actuel dans un fichier pour continuer lors d&amp;rsquo;une prochaine éxécution, sauf si la partie est terminée.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complete NS3 with DCE installation on Ubuntu 16.04 and 17.04</title>
      <link>https://bullekeup.github.io/blog/ns3-dce-ubuntu-16-4-17-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 15:43:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bullekeup.github.io/blog/ns3-dce-ubuntu-16-4-17-4/</guid>
      <description>I recently installed NS3 to benchmark different network applications and protocol implementations such as libcoap. I used different VMs with either Ubuntu 16.04 LTS or Ubuntu 17.04 to run NS3, and since I encountered many difficulties to make all modules successfully build and work, here are some patches to overcome common problems (may not be optimal, take it as a bunch of hints.
NOTE: This applies only for NS3 installation via bake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[HOWTO] Create a bootable Windows 10 EFI USB device on Linux</title>
      <link>https://bullekeup.github.io/blog/howto-bootable-win10-efi-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 17:49:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bullekeup.github.io/blog/howto-bootable-win10-efi-linux/</guid>
      <description>WARNING: Your USB device will be totally erased from all content ! Do a backup if needed !
Very small howto, just because I found many people who doesn’t know how to create a Windows 10 bootable USB device with EFI support.
To make it short, to boot with EFI on modern computers (less than 5-6 years – both laptop and desktop – ) all you need is love a device with a GPT partition table and a FAT32 partition (called an ESP partition) containing Windows 10 files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNU Tools on Windows with Cygwin and Vcxsrv</title>
      <link>https://bullekeup.github.io/blog/gnu-tools-windows-cygwin-vcxsrv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 18:41:32 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bullekeup.github.io/blog/gnu-tools-windows-cygwin-vcxsrv/</guid>
      <description>Like I said before in my Windows 10 review, I decided to try out Windows 10 as my work machine. If the global experience after two weeks is not that glorious, I still have some interesting little things for GNU/Linux enthusiasts stuck with Windows for whatever reason.
As I can’t decently work without a GNU environment, a decided to give Cygwin and VcXsrv a try.
Quick reminder, Cygwin is</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Win10 Review</title>
      <link>https://bullekeup.github.io/blog/win10-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 18:14:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bullekeup.github.io/blog/win10-review/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft recently took my attention thanks to its open-source move for a lot of their .NET core framework, and a bunch of other libraries (see Microsoft’s github).
Add to that their recent partnership with Red Hat and Canonical, and the idea of testing the last Windows release suddenly came to my mind. Last factor : my recent issues with Xen and ATI Drivers on Win 7 virtual machine, and the lack of time to resolve them for now, leave me with no other choice than moving to Windows for gaming.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>